# **Sheffer Fernandes**

Mumbai, Maharashtra • +91 82864 53438 • shefferf@ymail.com • linkedin.com/in/sheffer-fernandes-465450bb

## **Senior Software Engineer**

A hardworking Senior Sofware Engineer having over 7+ years of experience in creating webApplications, desktop applications, and **REST** APIs using various technologies and frameworks. I am skilled in Java, Spring Boot, JPA, HTML, JavaScript, JSTL, JQuery, Go lang, MySQL, XMPP, MQTT, encryption, retrofit Library, Jx browser, Jasper reports and software version control. I have successfully delivered projects for various Clients and received positive feedback and testimonials for my outstanding work. I am seeking to join a leading ecommerceCompany where I can use my technical expertise and problem-solving skills to contribute to its growth and success

#### SKILLS

- Programming Languages: Java, Golang, SOL
- Development Frameworks: Spring Boot, Spring Security, Hibernate, JPA OAuth 2, Retrofit, JasperReports, JavaFx, Paho
- Databases :- MySQL, NoSQL (Elastic Search), SQLite
- Build Tools:- Maven
- Version Control :- Git, SVN
- Development Environment :- Windows

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

### Point Pi/Lexi Devices Inc • Mumbai, Maharashtra, India

03/2020 - 10/2023

#### **Senior Software Engineer**

- In my most recent role at Point Pi, I migrated a Spring project from Java 1.6 to Java 11 with Spring Boot, resolving compatibility issues and improving code quality.
- Utilized **Spring Security** to implement **Oauth 2** protocol for secure authentication and authorization.
- · Leveraged Java 11 and Spring Boot with JPA to create REST APIs for efficient and scalable data management.
- Developed a common jar file and integrated it as a dependency in other modules, reducing code duplication and complexity.
- Utilized HTML, JavaScript, JSTL, JOuery, Java 11 and Spring to create and modify web pages according to given requirements, ensuring functionality and compatibility across browsers and devices.
- Developed Charts & Graphs with HighCharts, visualizing data and trends in an engaging and informative way.
- Utilized Paho library to create a MQTT client that connects and publishes to a MQTT broker, facilitating efficient and robust communication between devices.
- Utilized Go lang to create a MQTT service to connect and subscribe to a MQTT broker and save data to a
- NoSQL database (Elastic Search), facilitating high-performance and adaptable data management.
- Developed AWS Lambda function and wrote code in python to communicate with our in house IOT devices, enabling serverless and cost-effective device management.

## Sanda Office Management Services Pvt. Ltd • Mumbai, Maharashtra, India **Software Developer**

04/2018 - 03/2020

- During my tenure at Sanda Office Management Services Pvt. Ltd, I developed several Modules using JavaFx for given Project in Desktop.
- Developing and Implementation with Xmpp for the given Project in both Android and Desktop.
- Implementation of RSA and AES Keys for Encryption in Several Modules.
- Implementation of Retro Fit Library to call REST APIs in Both Android and Desktop Application.
- Developed Rest APIs using SpringBoot. Implementation of Jx Browser Integrated into JavaFx in Desktop.

# Immortal Computer Lab Icl • Mumbai, Maharashtra, India

## Java Software Developer

- During my tensure at ICL, I created a Software Version Control Utility and administered the same
- Designing, Developing and Implementing Several Integrated Modules of EMSS and ICLIGM Software.
- Jasper Reports Implementation and Administration for both EMSS and ICLIGM Software.
- Installation/Deployment and Testing the EMSS and ICLIGM software. Managing multiple projects simultaneously from conception through completion.

## **EDUCATION**

Bachelor of Science in Information Technology University Of Mumbai • Mumbai, Maharashtra, India	2015
Science S.M. Shetty Jr. College • Mumbai, Maharashtra, India	2012
Evangelist High School • Mumbai, Maharashtra, India	2010

03/2016 - 03/2018